fearlessdining.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy - Fearless Dining

This privacy policy sets out how Sandi Gaertner and Fearless Dining uses and protects any information that you give while using the www.fearlessdining.com website.

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Fearless Dining and Sandi Gaertner may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from September 1, 2013 to present.

 **Personal Information Collected**

You are welcome to browse this Website without providing any information about yourself. However, if you choose to contact us, leave a comment on a post, subscribe to our newsletter, opt-in to receive a download, or make a purchase, we will collect “Personal Information”, including your name, email address, and IP address.

 **What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service.

Personal Information we collect may be used as follows:

  * To improve the user experience of our Website.
  * To execute a giveaway, contest, survey, or other site feature.
  * To promote our content on social media or other places on the Internet.

 **Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

If there is a data breach, you will be notified within 72 hours.

If you want to have your data removed, you have the right to be forgotten. Contact us and we will remove your data promptly.

 **How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes, and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

 **Information Collected Through Google Analytics**

Fearless Dining uses Google Analytics to collect traffic data. All websites which collect traffic data, which is more than 1/2 of all websites on the Internet, have the ability to monitor visitor information such as IP addresses, browser type, operating system, location, date/time of visit, and information about which areas of the site are visited. The data is anonymous and does not personally identify you. It is used solely for improving the user experience of our audience as a whole.

In compliance with the GDPR, our Google Analytics does not store your full IP address. Instead, the last octet of your IP is reset to zeros before any processing or storing takes place. This means that it cannot be used to identify you at all. If you want to opt out of Google Analytics, you please contact us at sandi@fearlessdining.com do so.

Google Analytics data retention expires after 14 months and resets on new activity.

The plugins used on this site and social media sites are compliant with GDPR.

 **Advertising**

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website.

Ads are placed by MediaVine, Google Adsense, and Amazon.com

These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

You can also opt out of cookies using the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page at this page;  
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

Finally, you can choose to disable or selectively turn off cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings.

 **Information Collected Via Submissions**

When you leave comments, fill out submission forms, or email us, you have the option of providing your name, blog or website url, or other information. This Personal Information may become a permanent part of the Website when you provide it with a comment and can be seen by other visitors to the site. The email address field supplied when leaving a comment will not be publicly displayed.

 **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

• whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes  
• if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

 **Sale of Information**

We do not sell any information about users of our site.

 **Security of information**

Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your Personal Information with third parties, unless required by law. Data is stored securely without access by unauthorized parties.

 **Children’s Oline Privacy Protection ACT**

We comply with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act). We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under 13 years of age. The content of this Website is directed at adults, not children. Please contact us immediately if you find a child under 13 using this Website.

 **Third Party Websites**

This Website provides links to other websites for your convenience. Fearless Dining has no control over and assumes no liability for the actions, products, services, content, privacy policies, or terms of these sites. Please review their policies before proceeding.

If you wish to opt out of email newsletters or push notifications, you can do this on your own. Use the unsubscribe link from the newsletter, or remove the push notification from your browser, respectively.

In compliance with the GDPR, we will erase all data on our side upon request. For any data that resides on your computer, such as cookies or push notification opt-in, you would need to remove it yourself.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact me at sandi@fearlessdining.com
